Christopher M. Miller

linkedin.com/in/christophermllr

Chicago, IL 60618 219.689.4294 cmiller0189@gmail.com

Professional Profile

Christopher Miller is a Senior Technology Architect specializing in application strategy, architecture, design, and development. He brings over eight years of experience developing solutions using technologies like ASP.NET, Angular, JavaScript, and Microsoft Azure and has led our delivery teams through multiple complex engagements. Primarily focused on helping our Energy and Utilities clients as they navigate an evolving technology landscape, Christopher has also developed applications and advised clients on technology strategy across the healthcare, retail, food science, private equity, and higher education industries.

Experience

Senior Architect, West Monroe Partners | Chicago, IL

Mar 2019 — Present

- Led implementation of WMP's ConnectTheGrid[™] product for managing the approval and deployment of distributed energy resource (DER) assets at a large, multi-state electric utility
- Designed a future state enterprise architecture/strategy for back-office systems at a large healthcare professional association

Architect, West Monroe Partners | Chicago, IL

Oct 2015 — Feb 2019

- Advised a large healthcare professional association on technology modernization strategy and SDLC process improvements
- Managed delivery teams across multiple ConnectTheGrid™ projects including payment integration and public API management
- Led modernization efforts for a large benefits administrator's core platform technology and software development processes
- Executed an intranet platform assessment for a large utility and created a customer data IT strategy roadmap for a large retailer
- Managed and delivered development projects for a large medical equipment manufacturer's inventory management system.
- Managed and delivered development projects for a global food testing organization's lab result system
- Executed an SDLC assessment for a global payment processing company to optimize their development organization
- Performed over ten technical software due diligence projects for private equity clients

Senior Consultant, West Monroe Partners | Chicago, IL

Oct 2013 — Oct 2015

- Designed and developed initial release of WMP's ConnectTheGrid[™] product
- Developed an SSIS package and management application for syncing a client's investment documents to a cloud-hosted portal

Experienced Consultant, *West Monroe Partners* | Chicago, IL Consultant, *West Monroe Partners* | Chicago, IL

Oct 2012 — Oct 2013

Jun 2011 — Oct 2012

Education

B.S. with Highest Distinction, Computer and Information Technology, *Purdue University* | West Lafayette, IN Certificate in Entrepreneurship & Innovation, *Purdue University* | West Lafayette, IN

Dec 2010 Dec 2010

Technical Qualifications

- Back-end development: ASP.NET, Java/Spring, and Python
- Front-end development: Angular/TypeScript, AngularJS/JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, jQuery, Bootstrap
- Data: Microsoft SQL Server, SQL Azure, Apache Cassandra, DataStax Enterprise
- Management: Agile, engagement lead, and technical architecture experience with mid-sized teams of 3-7 developers
- Deployment/administration: Azure App Service, Azure Service Bus, other Azure components, IIS, SQL Server, Jenkins CI

Certifications and Publications

- Microsoft Certified Web Developer: Web Applications, Certified Cassandra Architect, and DataStax Certified Architect
- Sheppard, Dennis, Christopher Miller, and A. J. Liptak. AngularJS for. NET Developers in 24 Hours. Sams: Indianapolis, IN, 2015. Print.